## TECH / SKILLS

HTML **UX DESIGN** CSS **UI DESIGN BOOTSTRAP** WIRE-FRAMING **JAVASCRIPT** PROTOTYPING **JQUERY USER RESEARCH** REACT MOCK UPS **EXPRESS GRAPHIC DESIGN** NODE.JS PHOTOGRAPHY NEXT IS **IMAGE EDITING MONGODB** GIT/GITHUB WORDPRESS HEROKU

#### **SOFTWARE**

VS CODE PHOTOSHOP
BOOTSTRAP STUDIO LIGHTROOM
AXURE RP ILLUSTRATOR
MS OFFICE ADOBE XD

### **SOFT SKILLS**

CRITICAL THINKING AUTHENTICITY

COMMUNICATION TIME MANAGEMENT

FAST LEARNER RELIABILITY

DETAIL ORIENTATED INDEPENDANT

### **PERSONAL**

Birthday : 11 April 1994

Nationality : South African & Greek

Languages : English

### **CONTACT**



Claremont, Cape Town, South Africa



+27 84 413 5465



nikitabatlis@live.com



https://nikitabatlis.github.io/portfolio/

## NIKITA BATLIS

## Web Developer

#### **PROFILE**

I thrive on creative front-end challenges and enjoy implementing UI trends into my current projects. I have a particular interest in accessible UX design and believe the key to a product's long-term success is putting the user's experience first.

I spent 4 years working on yachts and in hospitality, before returning home to continue my education and transition to a career in Web Development and UX/UI design. Having completed my boot-camp and diploma, I am looking for a graduate/junior position within a strong team to further my industry knowledge.

Equipped with a conscientious work ethic - I am a reliable, proactive colleague with a keen eye for detail, and will never skip an opportunity to learn something new.

#### **EDUCATION**

# FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

HYPERIONDEV, CAPE TOWN

A full MERN stack web development course that taught me to build dynamic, data-driven web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Express & React.

# BRAND & MARKETING MANAGEMENT

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Part time 6 month course to develop both theoretical and practical knowledge in the field of brand building and digital marketing.

# PROFESSIONAL DIPLOMA IN UX DESIGN

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE, IRELAND

Correspondence 1 year diploma in professional UX design user theory, research methods, prototyping and wireframing work-flows, as well as design thinking and analysis.

2019 - 2020

# CERTIFICATE IN COMMERCIAL PHOTOGRAPHY

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Full time 2 year certification in professional photography, image editing and manipulation, as well as graphic design.

2013 - 2014

#### **JOB HISTORY**

### Photographer & Worpress Designer

Apr 2019 - Present

Freelance Student | Cape Town

Commissioned portraiture, location and real estate photography. As well as specialized Wordpress website designs for small local businesses.

### Location Scout & Researcher

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

Cape Town Productions | www.ctprod.co.za | Cape Town

A summer contract managing and updating the company's location database while researching and scouting new locations around Cape Town. Along with assisting on set and in-office coordinators.

### Stewardess Dec 2017 - Sep 2018

Katara | 123m Private Motor Yacht | Spain

Working & living closely with a team of 70 multinationals. Managing & maintaining luxury yacht interiors while delivering 10 Star service for Arab Royalty.

#### Junior Stewardess

Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

Lady Nag Nag | 53m Motor Yacht | *France & Monaco* Seasonal contract on board a demanding, fast pased privately owned yacht.

REFERENCES UPON REQUEST